Johandry Amador

San Diego, California, USA. 92129 +1 (858) 999 4228 Johandry@qmail.com



OBJECTIVE

DevOps Engineer, Sys Admin and Unix & Web developer, working on a challenging and rewarding position where I can continue learning and using all my knowledge. In companies that can utilize a performance driven individual; providing cost-effective solutions and implementing quality driven environments.

SUMARY

More than 15 years of experience in Unix administration, Unix development (Shell, Perl & Ruby) and Middleware administration for several 500 Fortune companies. Working as DevOps Engineer for more than 2 years but doing DevOps like activities since 10 years ago. Project Manager, QA Manager and ITIS Technical Leader for 5 years. More than 10 years of experience in Programming languages, Scripting languages and Web Development Frameworks.

SKILLS

Programming, Scripting and other Languages

Perl, Ruby, Shell (Bash), Java Script, HTML5, JSON, CSS SQL and Python.

Frameworks, Runtime Environments and Development Tools

Dancer, Rails, JQuery, AngularJS and NodeJS.

Configuration Management and DevOps Tool

Puppet, Docker, Vagrant, Packer, Jenkins, Foreman, AWS, SoftLayer, OpenShift 2 & 3 and Git.

Networking and SysAdmin tools

F5, Zabbix, Nagios, Keynote, vSphere, OKTA, CA Siteminder, SUN Identity Management and CA Autosys.

Database Server

SQLite, MySQL and MongoDB.

Middleware

Apache Web Server, Tomcat, JBoss and Glassfish.

Systems

Linux (RedHat, CentOS, Ubuntu, Debian), Unix (HP-UX, OS X) and Windows.

Soft Skills

Project Management including: Remotely and On-site coordination of more than 30 teams top in different countries, People Management 1:12, Metrics Reviews, Risk Management, Process Management, Change Management, Release Management, Incident and Problem Management, Planning and coordination of System Integration Tests and UATs, Retailing processes, basic Logistics process and basic Financial and Managerial Accounting.

Other

MS Project, HP Quality Center, Service Now, Jive and Single Sign On.

Professional Experience

FICO, San Diego, CA, USA

DevOps Engineer

Responsibilities:

- Development of Puppet modules with Hiera, r10k and Jenkins for continue integration and continue deployment of managed products and related services.
- Control of version and repository management with BitBucket and Git.
- Use of Foreman, Foreman API and Vagrant to lifecycle management of virtual servers in Non-Production environments on VirtualBox and vSphere.
- Task automation, service management and application deployment using Bash scripting, Puppet modules with Hiera and Jenkings.
- Use of Docker and OpenShift to manage micro services for development and testing.
- Server virtualization management and basic storage management with vSphere.
- Use of Packer to generate images to be used with Vagrant on VirtualBox and vSphere.
- Ownership and support of 7 Products with 3 layers in Non-Production environments.
- Design of Infrastructure Diagrams, creation of Bills of Materials (BoM) and validation of Software Architecture Document (SAD).
- Administration of JBoss and Glassfish, manually and with Puppet.
- Use of F5 to configure load balance and high availability.

2015-Present

- Creation and management of VIP with NPM and F5. DNS management with Infoblox.
- Single Sign On configuration with OKTA with the OKTA Console and at the application side, manually and with puppet
- Zabbix and Keynote configuration for monitoring and reporting of every server and service in Production and Non-Production environment and on the 3 layers.
- Configuration of SSL/TLS in every application layer and configuration of mutual authentication, manually and using puppet.
- Management, manually and with puppet, of: MySQL, CouchBase, ElasticSearch, Vertica, Jasper, Apache Web Server, Apache MQ, Apache Tomcat.
- Installation and configuration on the server side (UNIX) of Vormetric.
- Installation and upgrade of Tableau Server.
- Use of ServiceNow for incident management, change control and task management using Visual Task Boards and KanBan system.
- Documentation of processes as well as scripts on Jive and git server (Markdown).

Global HITSS, Aquascalientes, Mex.

Senior System Administrator and UNIX Developer (Perl, Bash, Ruby & Web)

Worldwide Attended Business: Amdocs, AT&T and Yellow Pages.

Responsibilities:

- UNIX developer in Perl and Bash to automate UNIX Admin tasks.
- Perl developer of Web and RESTful Application (backend) using Dancer2 framework with MySQL and MongoDB. All these using Packer, Vagrant and Docker.
 Web developer (frontend) using AngularJS, JQuery, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS and JS. All these using
- Yeoman, NPM, Bower, Grunt and NodeJS.
- Build and Configuration Management of development/testing environments with Docker, Fig, Packer, Vagrant and Puppet on VirtualBox running on Windows and Mac and AWS.
- Deployments to multiple servers in testing and production environments using Jenkins, Git and Docker.
- Documentation and Configuration Management of 200+ servers with Puppet and Git using Hiera and Hiera-eyaml.
- Development and Maintenance of a Job Scheduler application, a critical enterprise application similar to Autosys - to transfer remote files and execute remote commands. The transfers and executions are triggered by a schedule or the existence of a file (file watcher). The application can be executed form CLI or Web. The backend was developed in Perl on Dancer with a Database in MySQL and Bash scripts. The frontend was developed using HTML5, CSS, JS, JQuery and Bootstrap.
- Development and Maintenance of Web Application to centralize UNIX Admin tools and reports. This is a CLI and Web Application to collect and present reports of System Patches, Netapp differences, Nagios monitoring dashboard, Servers Inventory using Facter and others, the application is continuously growing. The backend is a RESTful application developed with Perl, Dancer2 using Moo (Perl Object Oriented), Bash and storing data on MongoDB. Use of JSON files to transfer data to the frontend, which was developed with AngularJS, JQuery, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS & JS. A second and improved version of this application was done using MEAN instead of LAMP. Using NodeJS with Express in the backend connected to MongoDB to store all the servers' data. The backend is a RESTful application as well to provide data to the frontend developed with AngularJS, Bootstrap and HTML5.
- Migration of 100+ servers and applications to the IBM cloud infrastructure (SoftLayer) using Puppet and Git to document and configuration management.
- Sys Admin activities such as Storage Management with NetApp, Server Virtualization Management with VMWare and General Svs Admin tier/level 1 tasks.
- Systems Administrator (Windows, RedHat ES and HPUX)
- On-Call service non-business hours every 6 weeks.

Softtek Information Services, Aguascalientes, Mex.

Technical Leader of Production Control Team, Senior System Administrator and Middleware Administrator Worldwide Attended Business: Electronic Arts, Burger King and General Electric Infrastructure Shared/Cloud Services.

Responsibilities:

- Systems Administrator (Redhat ES, HP-UX, CentOS and Windows 8) of +100 virtual and bare metal servers.
- Active participation in a Datacenter Migration. Accountable for Autosys servers and service.
- Project Manager in Electronic Arts of Global Data Centers Migrations of games, based on Blaze technology, to QA and Production environments.
- Middleware Administrator (Apache HTTP 2, JBoss 5 and 6).
- Deployments to JBoss manually and using automated homemade tools.
- Deployments of games in Electronic Arts based on Blaze manually and homemade scripts.
- Development of Perl, Shell (Bash) scripts, Ruby, C# and PowerShell (Windows) to automate SysAdmin tasks and Autosvs tools.
- Development of an Inventory web application (Ruby on Rails) to store Servers, Applications, Services, Owners and their attributes with an easy search and relationship among them.
- SSO enable applications using CA Siteminder.
- Troubleshooting of incidents with Apache Web Server, Proxies, SSO Siteminder, client side (JS, cookies, etc...), and applications running on JBoss.
- CA Autosys Administrator and System Administrator of 12 servers running Autosys agents.
- Autosys Jobs scheduling and troubleshooting of jobs for Windows and UNIX scripts, SAP, Informatica and Hyperion.

2013-2015

2012-2013

- Development of an Autosys CMDB, Autosys Jobs cleanup and Autosys Servers cleanup applications.
- Setup of a Knowledge Base using a Wiki on SharePoint to document the processed and best practice.
- Management of the cross-training of the Production Control team members.
- Development of plugins in Perl and Python for Nagios and Cactis to monitoring the Game Servers in Electronic Arts.

Softtek Information Services, International Integration Center, Aquascalientes, Mex.

UAT Program Manager, QA Manager, Program Manager, Project Manager and Business Analyst. Worldwide Attended Business: **Wal-Mart** Information System Division (ISD). Responsibilities:

- UAT Program Manager: Remotely (from Mexico) and on-site (from Brazil) planning, execution and control of the UAT to integrate Brazil SE Stores to Wal-Mart Systems.
 Program Manager: Remotely (from Mexico) and on-site (from US) coordination of 33 teams in US, Mexico
- Program Manager: Remotely (from Mexico) and on-site (from US) coordination of 33 teams in US, Mexico
 and Central America (Costa Rica, Nicaragua, Guatemala, Honduras and El Salvador) to integrate Stores
 and Distribution Centers to Wal-Mart systems from these 5 countries. Includes Development, System
 Integration Test and UAT's.
- Project Manager 1:12 of a Development using an ETL. Includes the phases Analysis, Design and Construction.
- The platform and technical distribution of the teams in all these projects were: 50% of the teams UNIX based, 30% of the teams Mainframe based and 20% of the teams functional.
- Hands-On on many UNIX technical issues and technical coordination on Mainframe technical issues.
- Planning, control and execution of technical and data environment setup for all the tests: SIT and UAT.
- Support to other Wal-Mart Integration programs such as Chile and Japan.
- Managerial reporting to high-level management.
- Business assessment, definition and documentation to implement a new business service in Softtek.
- Definition, installation and configuration of Knowledge Base tool.
- Instructor in academies to new resources in subjects like Shell and Perl programming, and Wal-Mart infrastructure and retailing processes.

Softtek Information Services, Aguascalientes, Mex.

Quality Manager, Project Manager, Technical Manager, Infrastructure Architect, Java Programmer, UNIX developer, administrator and Service support

Worldwide Attended Business: **General Électric** Treasury, GE Commercial Finances, GE Corporate Information Services, GE Finances and GE Corporate Initiative Group. Responsibilities:

- Project Technical manager 1:7.
- ITIL Process definition, documentation, implementation and management for the Release, Change, Knowledge, Configuration, Incident and Problem management processes of the project.
- Incident and Problem manager of SUN Identity Manager Infrastructure (IdM) using tools like Bugzilla for tracking and UNIX tools and Splunk to incident analysis.
- Change and Release Manager based on ITIL, using version control tools such as CVS, Subversion, Git and scripts to automate releases.
- Install, setup, support and maintenance of Knowledge Base applications.
- Design, Development with Ruby on Rails, Support and Maintenance of a CMDB application to keep the inventory of the infrastructure of the project (servers, OS, services, applications, users, etc...).
- Infrastructure Architect in charge of the Design and Implementation of the entire infrastructure of SUN Identity Manager Infrastructure (IdM) and Verdasys Digital Guardian at GE Commercial Finance.
- Install and Setup of an Enterprise Data Loss Prevention server application (Digital Guardian by Verdasys) to be used in the client company (GE). Setup of the Digital Guardian clients and definition of the policies to be used in the users computers.
- Installation and configuration of SUN Identity Manager (IdM) in 4 different environments (Development, QA, Stage and Production)
- Support and Maintenance of 18 UNIX servers (Web, Application, Database and Load Balancer) in 4 different environments (Development, QA, Stage and Production) used by SUN IdM
- Install, setup, support and maintenance of monitoring applications such as Topaz, Sitescope, Big Brother, Big Sister and Nagios to monitoring of 18 UNIX servers and services to prevent in advance possible incidents.
- Design and Development in Perl (Web) of a monitoring application and to execute administrative tasks on the services.
- UNIX scripting development in Bash, Perl and Ruby (Web and CLI) to automatize process for Release of code, Access Control, QA, Monitoring and Services Administration, reducing the work man hours and improving the processes.
- Install, Setup, Support and Maintenance of WebLogic, then JBoss, Apache and F5 to use the SUN Identity Manager (IdM) in a load balanced, concurrent and secure (HTTPS) cluster.
- Tuning of IdM, Java VM and WebLogic (then JBoss) to improve IdM performance.
- Infrastructure QA manager to plan and execute test such as Load Performance, Stress, Regression and Security Testing using tools like HP LoadRunner
- L1 Oracle 9i Administrator
- SSO enable of SUN IdM.
- UNIX Application support in Solaris
- Support and maintenance of Java Financial applications on the Web.
- Development of a Java Web Financial application.
- Support and Maintenance of Perl applications.

2008-2012

2004-2008

- Support and Maintenance of Perl and Bash Shell scripts used for SSO. Administration and monitoring of Solaris, Linux and Windows 2000 Servers.
- Users support.

Education

B.S., Computer Sciences, *Havana University, Havana, Cuba* 4.34/5.00 GPA

2000

Master of Business Administration ITESM Campus Aguascalientes, Mexico

Incomplete

Green Belt Certification Softtek, Aguascalientes, Mex.

2006

LANGUAGES

- Spanish 100% Native Speaker
- English 90% Very Good
- Portuguese Brazil 50% Good

Bilingual Spanish-English